Simply
Die
Heart attack
Yagami Light
Excuse us, please make way.
Thank you!
Amane Misa
Bye-bye!
See you again, everyone!
Misa-Misa's damn cute, huh?
She really cheers you up.
Want to grab a bite?
Sorry, I have work.
They're short-handed,
so they asked me to come.
Seriously?
Then how about we eat at your place?
Sure, but don't count on
getting my employee discount.
You figured me out?
Of course.
Pub Yonosuke
Yagami-kun, you want a public sector job?
Well, job security. There's no risk
of them going out of business.
Don't you have any ambition?
Like hitting it big and getting rich?
Once you get greedy, there's no end.
You can invest your life in something,
and it might make you money,
but it won't necessarily make you happy.
If I get really desperate,
I hope you'll give me a job here.
Desperate, huh? We have an employment
exam here, too, you know.
I suppose so.
You could do it if you applied yourself.
You've always beaten me on grades.
You could aim a bit higher
if you worked at it.
No thanks. No thanks.
Here.
I appreciate it.
He's so fast on register.
You're praising me for that?
As long as I can feed myself
Well, I make it a point
not to overexert myself.
and spend my days in peace and
stability, that's all I need.
Check please!
Sure!
Pub Yonosuke
Welcome!
What's this?
Hey, is that Kamoda I see?
It's me, Sakota!
And you're Yagami, right?
You know each other?
We were classmates in high school.
Oh, I see! Have a seat.
Here you are.
How's it look?
Thanks.
Hey, wait. Pour his beer for him.
I've been in a study abroad
program all this time.
I ended up coming back sooner than expected.
Surprised?
No, you were in jail.
Just hand it over!
That sucks. This won't be enough.
Who's next?
What are you glaring at?
Nothing.
Oh, well.
Next up is rich boy Kamoda. Come along.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three—
Too bad!
I'll hold onto the Guinness application fee.
Wow, you're loaded!
Oh... it's nothing.
I hope we can pick up where we left off.
What do I do, Light?
I... he's going to go back to...
Kamoda. Bring 300,000 tomorrow.
Got it?
Stop this.
Stop doing this.
I never liked the way you looked at me.
Give that back.
When Kamoda comes with the 300,000, I will.
Let's have a nice, long acquaintance.
I wish guys like him
would just go away forever.
Yagami
I'm home.
If you're not gonna watch it, turn it off.
You're running up our electricity bill.
Hey, I was watching!
Where's Dad?
Staying at work again.
Yagami Sayu
Hey, I'm hungry.
Cook for yourself for once. I'm tired.
Stingy.
Death... Death Note?
"How to use it"...
English?
Longman Japanese-English Dictionary
The human whose name is written
in this note shall die.
This note will not take effect unless
the writer has the person's face
in their mind when writing his or her name.
Therefore, people sharing the
same name will not be affected.
If the cause of death is
written within 40 seconds
of writing the person's name, it will happen.
If the cause of death is not specified, the
person will simply die of a heart attack.
Utter nonsense.
Ow...
Let's have a nice, long acquaintance.
I wish guys like him would
just go away forever.
Sakota Genbu
This is stupid.
My brother's?
Yes.
Hey, bro. Do you know a guy called Sakota?
Yagami Light-san?
Yes.
We checked the contents of the phone
and we're pretty sure it's yours.
We found it in Sakota-san's jacket pocket.
U-Um...
He said the guy died.
Died?!
Oh, water's boiling.
Last night around 11:30 he ran his
motorcycle into a railroad crossing
while the gate was down.
It seems he died instantly.
Were the two of you acquainted?
Yagami-san?
Y-Yes. Um... we were
classmates in high school.
Er, but we never hung out much...
Yesterday, we just happened to
run into each other at my job...
I must have dropped it and
he picked it up for me.
I see! Well, goodbye.
Thank you for your trouble.
The human whose name is written
in this note shall die.
If the cause of death is not specified, the
person will simply die of a heart attack.
But he died in an accident.
Hey, where's breakfast?
I'm gonna be late.
Right. I'll make it now.
I'll have toast today. Toast.
Site of the Late Genbu
Sakota's Funeral and Wake
Scared the hell out of me yesterday.
The way Sakota was just riding along
and suddenly doubled over in pain.
What's wrong?
Hey! Sakota!
Then he splatted right into that train.
What the hell was that, anyway?
A heart attack, they said.
Heart attack?
Yeah.
N-No... no...
No way...
No way... No way...
Look at you, grinning.
We're at a wake, you know.
Come on.
Just between us,
Sakota did nothing but make trouble
for people when he was alive, right?
Look at these posts from
his graduating class.
Deep down, they're all relieved he's dead.
Take that, Sakota! lololololol
Hey, Yuki, that's so rude!
"Take that, Sakota"?
A lot of people hated school because of him.
Dying's the nicest thing he ever did.
Seriously. He scared me so I did
everything I could to avoid him.
"Dying's the nicest thing he ever did."
Scum of the earth = Sakota
Sakota had no value alive anyway.
"Sakota had no value alive anyway."
Yesterday, a man died.
But a lot of people aren't sad.
They're actually happy.
Taxi Driver Robbery & Murder
Case Investigation Headquarters
Regarding the suspect who fled the scene
after killing a taxi driver and
stealing his fares this morning,
an image from the taxi's on-board camera
has confirmed it to be Otoharada Kuro,
Wanted
For robbery and murder
Otoharada Kuro
age 46, who was released
on parole a month ago.
Yagami Soichiro
Metropolitan Police Department Criminal Investigation Bureau
1st Division Chief Inspector
The house his guarantor set up for
him after parole was found empty.
We're putting up wanted posters and
we're trying to find where he is.
That's all.
Mogi Kanzo
Metropolitan Police Department Criminal Investigation Bureau
1st Division Assistant Inspector
So Otoharada's out, eh?
I want to see a thorough investigation.
And...
Yagami-kun, I'm counting on you.
Yes, sir.
Okay, dismissed!
Right!
Chief... This time...
Work with local authorities
in the investigation.
Matsuda Tota     Aizawa Shuichi
1st Division Officer        1st Division Sergeant
Metropolitan Police Department Criminal Investigation Bureau
I want a full report of the situation.
Yes sir. Of course.
That damned Ogiso,
throwing his weight around.
Now, now. Hold on.
The Chief is enduring it just like we are.
Hey, what happened between the
Chief and the suspect, Otoharada?
You hadn't heard?
Ten years ago, Otoharada got hopped up
on meth and went on a killing spree.
It was Chief who caught him.
The two of us wore through ten pairs of
shoes between us at the height of summer.
That must have cost a lot.
Matsuda! That's not what he's talking about.
No, I'm sure it is.
No! It's not about money, he's talking
about doing a lot of footwork!
But you can't do anything without money!
That was one expensive summer...
Yagami-san! You did it!
Great work!
Take Otoharada to the interrogation room.
Yes sir.
Just you wait... I'll kill you, too.
Shut it.
I'm gonna kill the hell
out of you! Just you wait!
You hear me? I'll kill you!
Yagami-san.
We got a call from the hospital.
Your wife's in critical condition.
Leave the rest to us.
Go to the hospital.
No, Otoharada takes priority.
I'll go to the hospital later.
Why didn't you come right away?
I called and I called!
Mama! Mama!
Dad!
I'm home.
Welcome home.
Hey, you had dinner?
Dad, you want a beer, right?
I got it cold for you and everything.
This is a shake-down for allowance, right?
Come on! Please!
Should I peel you an apple?
No.
Then I'll fetch you a snack.
Hey, where's Light?
I'm coming in.
Hey!
What?
You almost never come up to my room.
Making progress with your
public service exam?
Where did that come from?
It's nothing.
I'm hoping to get into the local ward office.
Even if that's wrong, I don't
plan to join the police.
I guess you wouldn't.
Oh, hey...
Murder...
What's this all of a sudden?
What about murder?
Those cases never stop, do they?
No matter how much you suffer for it...
I might be working long shifts for a while.
Take care of things here at home.
Hey, you. What are you doing over there?
We found a fare envelope from a taxi company
and a knife thought to be
the weapon used next to him.
Where's the officer's gun?
It's missing.
This is unfolding in the worst possible way.
Mogi-san!
A man carrying what looked like a handgun
has holed himself up in a
private residence in Meguro.
This sucks!
You can't kill someone
with something like this.
Morning!
Hey.
Hey, when did Dad head out?
Dunno.
I missed my chance to get allowance from him.
Hey, did you eat the apples over there?
Didn't Dad eat them?
All three?
Uh-oh, I gotta go.
Take your positions!
Otoharada Kuro, give yourself up.
We have you surrounded!
Give yourself up!
Shut up!
I'll freaking kill you!
Ah, heck.
That son of a bitch.
Chief.
How many hostages?
Two.
A housewife and her daughter
in elementary school.
Elementary school?
The longer we wait, the greater the
risk to those hostages becomes.
We should call the superintendent and
storm the place as soon as possible.
Sir!
Hold on.
Today's non-combustible trash.
Sorry.
1st Division, Matsuda-san
Call incoming
Matsuda-san.
Why did Dad make himself a hostage?
The chief made a deal with the suspect in
exchange for an elementary school girl.
What?
What the hell does Yagami think he's doing?
If there's one thing
I hate, it's grandstanding!
I'm sorry, sir.
We're evaluating the situation now...
The Chief has a history with the
man holed up in that building.
Apparently it was Chief
Yagami who arrested him,
back around the time your mother passed away.
What?
It's like he feels responsible for his
getting parole and committing crimes again—
Matsuda!
Sir?
What are you doing there?
Return to the scene!
Sir!
Sayu's in there. Later!
Sayu.
Brother...
Dad's...
Coming through! Clear the way!
How's the Chief?
It's not looking good, Mr. Mogi.
Otoharada.
You remember me, don't you?
You should be well aware
that this is pointless.
Just give up and turn yourself in already.
Why do you think I traded that kid for you?
You're the one that "should be well aware."
I'm gonna kill the hell
out of you! Just you wait!
I made a promise!
Live - Spree Killing Suspect
Holed Up with Hostages
The man holed up in the residence in broad
daylight, according to police investigations,
Live - Spree Killing Suspect Holed Up with Hostages
Suspect: Otoharada Kuro (46)
is Otoharada Kuro, age 46.
Early on the 20th, Otoharada allegedly
stabbed a taxi driver to death,
Otoharada...
took his fare money and fled...
Kill him.
Just kill that scum and save my dad already!
Just kill him!
Kill him already!
Sayu...
Otoharada Kuro
If you fire, the special forces out
there are going to storm the place.
If they do, I can't protect you.
You wouldn't anyway!
Even if you're a criminal, I want
to save all the lives I can.
Don't throw your life away, Otoharada.
Shut up. Shut up!
The atmosphere is tense.
The suspect has a handgun,
making it difficult for SWAT
to storm the residence.
The human whose name is written
in this note shall die.
If the cause of death is written within
40 seconds of writing the
person's name, it will happen.
If the cause of death is not specified, the
person will simply die of a heart attack.
Live - Spree Killing Suspect
Holed Up with Hostages
The suspect, Otoharada, holed up in
the house earlier with his hostages.
Live - Spree Killing Suspect Holed Up with Hostages
Suspect: Otoharada Kuro (46)
I repeat. The suspect is
Otoharada Kuro, age 46.
Otoharada... Kuro...
Then we'll go out together!
Death Note...
If you're the real thing...
Then kill him!
Otoharada Kuro
Ten...
Twenty...
Thirty...
Die!
Forty!
...is in there with a man with a gun.
It's a mentally taxing situation.
Live - Spree Killing Suspect
Holed Up with Hostages
Come out.
With great concern for the
safety of the two hostages...
Come out!
Live - Spree killing suspect
holed up with hostages
We've heard a gunshot! We heard what sounded
like a gunshot coming from the house.
Mogi-san!
Storm the place! Storm the place!
Moments ago, we heard what sounded
like a gunshot coming from the house,
and the SWAT team stormed the house.
Live - Spree Killing Suspect
Holed Up with Hostages
It looks like they're
bringing the hostages out!
The hostages are safe.
A 36 year old woman who lived in the house,
and the police officer who went inside
both appear to be evacuated safely.
Chief, are you okay?
I'm fine.
Right.
Chief. What was that gunshot?
An accidental discharge.
Otoharada suddenly staggered in pain...
Die!
What, like a heart attack?
I don't know.
Live - Spree Killing Suspect
Holed Up with Hostages
It appears the perpetrator
died inside the house.
The shot was not fired by
the hostage police officer.
It happened when the perpetrator suddenly
doubled over in pain and collapsed.
I repeat. The perpetrator...
Otoharada Kuro
It really is...
the real thing...
Dad!
I'm fine. Is Light here, too?
He ran off somewhere.
Really, he's so unreliable.
How could this have happened?
Otoharada Kuro
I would have been happy... just
letting the days pass uneventfully...
I killed...
two people.
I killed them.
Otoharada Kuro
I'm sorry.
Dad...
Feel like dying?
I'm the one who dropped that Death Note.
The Shinigami, Ryuk.
No need to act so surprised.
You already realized it's no
ordinary notebook, didn't ya?
How's it feel to do someone in?
Damn it!
Dad.
Sayu.
This is goodbye.
You don't want the Death Note, huh?
Just because you're possessed by a shinigami,
that's no reason to hurry to your death.
Isn't that right, Yagami Light?
Shinigami don't steal souls.
That's an idea you humans
dreamed up for yourselves.
That notebook became the
property of the human world
the minute it touched the
ground of the human world.
In other words, it belongs to you.
I don't want it.
Oh, yeah?
You sure about that?
Just write the name of any
human you want gone inside it,
and you can erase them from this world.
If you use it the right way, you
could become a very rich man.
But if you still don't want it,
I'll erase all your memories of the notebook.
Then...
th-that notebook...
That's right.
What if a real bastard like
those guys you killed,
Otoharada or Sakota,
picked up that notebook?
Things could get pretty interesting!
No!
The person who picks up the Death
Note gets to decide how they use it.
Wait! Wait!
I-In that case...
Wh-what does it cost to use it?
I think you already got a taste of the cost.
An agony and terror that only
the one who holds it can feel.
I killed... two people...
Any human who uses the Death Note
can't expect to get to go to Heaven or Hell.
Wh-Why...
did you...
Being a shinigami is awfully boring!
We live so long, we run out of things to do!
So...
I wanted to see what would happen
if a human started using it!
The deepest depths of human desire!
Yagami Light, what is it you desire?
Desire...
Well, you can decide for
yourself what you'll do.
One Month Later, England
What shall we do, sir?
Watari. Let's go to Japan.
I beg your pardon,
but the Japanese police haven't asked for
our assistance in their investigation yet.
Then get them to ask for our help.
Such a willful young man.
Tokyo
Kabeoka Hitoshi
It's the body of Hitoshi
Kabeoka, 40 years old.
He's wanted all over the country
on suspicion of murder.
We won't know the precise cause of
death until after the autopsy, but...
It's going to be heart failure
or a heart attack, right?
Looking that way.
Another one. That's 52 we
know of in just one month.
This is the 53rd.
And every single one of
them from heart attacks?
What the hell is going on here?
For the past month, similar mysterious
deaths have been occurring not just in Japan,
Heinous Criminal Serial Murder Case
Special Investigation Headquarters
but all over the world.
String of mysterious deaths of heinous criminals
Another criminal dies of heart attack
Body of man
found in city park
Shows linked to
string of heinous
criminal deaths
Mysterious deaths occurring worldwide
Shows connections to unexplained deaths occurring in Japan
Mysterious deaths
found abroad too
Heart attack again
Cause of death unclear
At first we considered that it could
be a virus or a mass neurosis,
but ICPO analysis denies that claim.
Yagami-kun.
It's worth mentioning that the
victims are all limited to
people convicted of crimes
classified as "heinous."
How are they being killed?
We don't know yet.
There are no external injuries, and the
cause of death in all cases is "heart attack."
Getting an early start to the day, huh?
Ryuk... Don't scare me like that.
Get used to it already.
Well? Who are today's candidates?
Five men.
Perpetrators of heinous crimes.
Their names and faces were announced
on the news this morning.
Hey, what's going on here?
Here.
Didn't I tell you not to wash my underwear?
Are you listening to me?
Then... wash it yourself.
And knock before you come in here.
I'm studying.
Who studies this early in the day?
She really can't see you, can she?
Isn't that interesting?
Only the person who touches the
Death Note can see me or hear me.
Of course, if she touched the notebook,
it would all be over anyway.
If that happened,
she wouldn't die of a heart attack,
she'd die of shock from seeing you.
Good point.
Hey, I beg your pardon!
We've discovered something
in the way of a motive.
What is it?
Himura-san.
Himura Shoko, from 2nd Criminal
Investigation Support Division.
Himura Shoko
Metropolitan Police Department Criminal Investigation Bureau Support and Analysis Center
Please look at this.
You're pretty good for a guy
with such an innocent face.
Hey,
how does this benefit you, exactly?
Can it make you rich?
It doesn't benefit me.
I'm doing this for the world.
Look at this.
What have we here?
The Legend of Kira, Our Savior
This is the voice of the world.
Kira?
It's a nickname, derived
from the word "Killer."
There's a number of other similar fan sites.
It's only been announced in the media as
"a string of mysterious deaths
among heinous criminals,"
but the people are realizing there's
a mastermind behind the killings,
"judging the wicked from the shadows."
Some are even lauding him.
Keep it up, Kira!
Please purge the wicked!
Thank you for killing those criminals, Kira!
You're calling this a
motive for the killings?
We have no conclusive evidence,
but we think our mastermind is after...
Keep it up, Kira!
Please purge the wicked!
Thank you for killing those criminals, Kira!
If I eliminate the criminals, people
can live their lives without fear.
I'm creating a peaceful world.
Cool!
Are we witnessing the birth of a hero?
I'm not a hero.
Hey, I want your autograph!
Write "To my friend Ryuk" right here!
Write it! Write it! Write it! Write it!
Hey...
Ryuk.
How many people have I killed?
Fifty?
No... 51?
No, no, no... 52?
I can't go back now, can I?
And I don't intend to.
I'd say the perpetrator's motive
is a twisted sense of justice.
Yes. I find a certain logic
in your speculation, Yagami-kun.
Oh, yes. I was just thinking that myself.
You liar.
Excuse me. I've brought Watari-san.
Go ahead.
I've brought in an outside consultant.
He's been investigating similar incidents
occurring in England and America
at the request of the ICPO.
My name is Watari.
I will be aiding you in this investigation.
Watari
L's Proxy
I serve as L's proxy.
"El"?
It's something like a nickname.
Despite being a famous person who's
solved numerous unsolved cases,
Mr. L prefers to be cautious and
not reveal his real name, right?
I request your understanding in this matter.
I'm going to create a peaceful world.
A world with no criminals.
Kira can change the world.
Humans are so interesting!
You know about Kira?
What do you think he's like?
Kira is God!
He's just a murderer.
The Legend of Kira, Our Savior
You're wrong. Kira is God.
Yeah, he's definitely God.
I'm bored. Anything interesting going on?
You know about Kira?
Who's that?
He must be God!
I'm bored. Anything interesting going on?
You know about Kira?
Who's that?
You know about the unexplained deaths of heinous criminals lately?
Yeah, I do!
They say it's because someone's bringing divine punishment down on them!
That's Kira. There's a website too.
What the hell lol
that's great lol
I wonder if it's a good thing.
He's no god. He's just a murderer.
Yeah, I do!
They say it's because someone's bringing divine punishment down on them!
That's Kira. There's a website, too.
What kind of person is Kira?
I want to meet Kira-sama!
Does this so-called Kira really exist?
Kira does exist. No, God is Kira.
He's begun his judgment of the wicked!
Kira Post Summary
If you list all the laws your precious Kira's broken,
it gets pretty amazing, lolol
Points in common between unexplained deaths!
More incidents of Kira cleaning up the scum of the earth
The truth behind the string of unexplained criminal deaths - Kira the God is issuing his judgment
Anonymous Kira Supporter
Wrong, Kira is God.
I love Kira!
The Legend of Kira, Our Savior
The police say they'll give
us their full cooperation.
I see. Then take care of this, too.
Another willful request.
Suginami University of Economics
Hey, Light.
Hey.
Hey sorry, but could I borrow your notebook?
Huh? Notebook?
Yeah, I had an interview with a
company and I missed the lecture.
I was hoping you'd let me look at it.
Oh, my class notebook.
Sure, go ahead.
Hey, Yagami-kun. What do you think of Kira?
Kira?
You think he's a murderer, right?
No, he's God, cleaning the world of scum.
Yagami-kun doesn't approve of
committing crimes. Right?
Yeah, of course.
What would you do if Misa-Misa was pro-Kira?
Huh?
See, I didn't know this, but...
It turns out Misa-Misa's family
was killed a long time ago.
Misa-Misa's got a lot on
her shoulders too, huh?
Public Prosecutors Office
Notice of Parole
Inmate Nishida Kyu
Parole?
At the hearing, the parole board
chose to allow Nishida's parole.
Mikami Teru
Tokyo Public Prosecutors Office
Public Prosecutor
I'm back!
Papa? Mama?
No!
But someone like him deserves to be executed!
I understand how you feel,
but the treatment of convicts
is decided fairly under the law.
Isn't it the law that judges the bad guys?
Then who is the law really protecting?
It's already been decided.
Excuse me.
Give... Give me back my family!
The defendant Kyu Nishida,
killer of a husband and wife in Maebashi
The defendant Kyu Nishida
Nishida...
this is the one...
Quit acting surprised every time!
This is a live broadcast from the
International Criminal Police Organization,
Hey, something interesting is going on.
the ICPO, to the whole world.
Yoshio Anderson will provide simultaneous
interpretation in Japanese.
My name is Lind L. Tailor,
otherwise known as L.
L?
I am investigating a string of
deaths among heinous criminals.
See? Interesting, huh?
I will do my utmost to hunt down Kira.
Kira, I have an idea of why you might
want to do something like this.
Should we really be broadcasting this?
The higher-ups made the
decision. Nothing we can do.
Be quiet and watch.
But no matter how brutal the criminals might
be, you have no right to judge people.
So Kira really exists?
Looks like...
What you're doing is evil.
Mikami Teru
Are the police declaring war on Kira?
Kira, are you watching this?
How are you killing these people?
He asked you a question.
You may be feeling like God,
but from my perspective, you're
just a hopeless, stupid murderer.
He has no idea!
Kira's protecting the peace, you know!
Stop judging the world by your yardstick.
He's going there?
He's just talking big because
there's nothing he can do.
Justice always wins.
No it doesn't. No it doesn't,
that's why Kira was born!
Kira. I will destroy your childish plans.
You think the police can
do something like this?
You can't!
You haven't made a dent in
the criminal population!
Do you really think you're needed?
It's making people happy.
It's saving a lot of people.
That's what Kira does!
The things you can't do... Kira can do!
Kira, I will send you to the gallows.
I won't let you... I won't let you stop Kira!
I will hunt you down.
Lind L. Tailor.
Ten...
Prepare yourself, Kira.
Thirty...
Forty...
Great work, Kira!
It's you...
It's your own fault.
Because you tried to get in Kira's way.
I can't believe this, Kira.
You can kill someone without direct contact?
What?!
The Lind L. Tailor you saw
on the broadcast today
was a convict due to be executed today.
In other words, a stand-in for me.
S-Stand in?
Kira.
If you don't like it, try to kill me again.
Go on. Do it.
Give it a try.
What's wrong? You can't do it?
I see.
There are people you can't kill, it seems.
Oops! He's got you there!
Oh, and one more thing.
I said the broadcast was going
out live to the whole world,
but it's actually only being
broadcast in Japan's Kanto region.
I'd planned to broadcast it in other
regions after some time had passed,
but there's no need for that now.
After all, you're in Kanto, aren't you, Kira?
Incredible.
Matsuda.
Sir, L just confirmed Kira's existence and
where he's hiding in one fell swoop.
Matsuda!
Pipe down.
You saw that he sacrificed
the life of a man to do it,
even if he was scheduled to die.
He's doing the same thing Kira is.
But that's no reason to just give
up and turn yourself in, Kira.
You're going to be found and your
method of killing exposed...
...by me.
He's good, huh?
Though he doesn't know your
name or what you look like...
L...
Well, not my business.
Ogiso, what is the meaning of this?
Well...
Get going!
Sir!
I want to talk to L directly.
Put me through.
Yes, sir.
Why couldn't Kira kill me if
he could kill my stand-in?
Faces?
L, I'm Yagami from the 1st Division.
Can you talk now?
Perfect timing.
The victims, the press
corps, and the internet...
I want you to run another
thorough investigation
on how the men who would become
victims were reported to the public.
What I want to know is—
There's something I want
to talk to you about first.
What do you think human life is?
If you're talking about my stand-in,
I got the ICPO's permission.
I don't care about permission.
Did you think there was a chance
that convict could be killed?
I don't reveal my face and name to anyone.
That's how I always do things.
Then what did you mean
when you said that Kira didn't
have to turn himself in?
It's the job of you, the police,
to arrest Kira, isn't it?
Just who is this guy?
How do you expect me to run an investigation
with someone who thinks the way you do?
How are we supposed to put our
lives in each other's hands?
Lives?
Yes. I don't think I'm exaggerating here.
We're putting our lives on the
line in this battle with Kira.
I want you to give that considerable thought.
Then, on the point about lives on
the line, I've realized something.
Kira can kill a person with
just their face and their name.
Just their face and their name?
Is he serious?
Shall I give you my profile on Kira?
Light!
Sorry, I know you're busy.
Here, it's a change of clothes for my dad.
That's so nice of you. Got it.
The Chief's been in a meeting for a while.
He'll probably stay again tonight.
Is this about the broadcast this afternoon?
Did you see it? L's incredible, huh?
Um...
What kind of person is L?
I can't disclose much,
but he's a great detective
who's solved a bunch of cases
in foreign countries that hit dead
ends, and he's a total unknown.
Unknown?
He won't reveal his face or
his name, even to the police.
But, well, with L's help, I'm sure the
Chief will be able to go home soon.
Does that mean... he seems
to know who Kira is?
This is between us, just between us.
The truth is, he's pretty close.
Kira Victims Death Time Comparison
As L indicated, there's a pattern
in the estimated times when people
believed to be killed by Kira died.
34% were killed between
8:00 PM and midnight.
42% were killed between
midnight and 3:00 AM.
This late-night focus suggests a strong
possibility that he's a student.
A student committed these murders?
Now about the way the victims
were covered in Japan,
they're all people we could confirm with
face and name on the news or the internet.
See? Just like I said.
Kira is a student living in the Kanto area
who can kill someone without direct contact,
as long as he knows their name and face.
Or something like that.
L is amazing!
From the fact that Kira retaliated
during the broadcast,
he determined that he's got a strong
exhibitionist streak and that he's young.
And the time frame of the crimes backed
up the idea that he's a student.
The time of the crimes...
Isn't there anything?
Anything?
This is it.
The public sector has better job
security than a corporation, huh?
Nowadays, anyway.
The time of the crimes has changed?
All the criminals who died from heart
attacks this week have done so during the day.
Does that cast doubt on L's
profile of him as a student?
New deaths believed to be perpetrated by Kira
Ugh..
Can we really trust L?
Maybe he's just jerking us around.
The Kira thing could just
be a one-man show he put on.
If the cause of death is written within
40 seconds of writing the person's name,
it will happen.
After writing the cause of death,
details of the death should be written
in the next six minutes and 40 seconds.
I get it.
You wrote 'heart attack',
but set the time later.
...will die of a heart attack at 11:00 AM.
...will die of a heart attack at 4:00 PM
...will die of a heart attack at 12:30 PM
Nice work!
Hopefully, if nothing else, they'll
abandon the idea that Kira is a student.
You managed to pull through, huh?
I think you'd be pretty good in battle!
Just what is going on?
Ogiso, can't you meet with L?
I'm sorry. L won't meet with anyone...
I'll meet you.
It's from L!
Put him on.
Y-Yes, sir!
But on have one condition.
Yagami Soichiro-san.
It must be you, alone.
That's the condition.
That's unusual. You never
invite people to meet you.
Did his scolding have an effect on you, then?
You like him, don't you?
Live - Spree killing suspect
holed up with hostages
It appears that the suspect
has died in the house. The hostage...
You don't meet many people who
can leave you speechless.
Get that list ready at once.
Before Yagami-san arrives.
Oh, this is...
The Legend of Kira, Our Savior
My boyfriend was killed by a slasher.
Please Kira, take revenge.
The person who killed my family has been released.
Please purge him.
The defendant Nishida Kyu,
killer of a husband and wife in Maebashi
Nishida, make an honest
living from now on, okay?
What's wrong? Hey, Nishida!
What's wrong? Nishida!
Died of a heart attack on the day of parole
Inmate Nishida Kyu
some believe it to be the work of Kira
Kira did this?
So sorry for the wait.
Please step this way.
This way.
Please leave your cell phone and
other communications devices here.
Right this way.
Your pardon. It's disinfectant.
He's a sensitive person in many ways.
Here we are.
So you're...
I'm L.
I'm Yagami Soichiro of the
Criminal Investiga—
Enough.
I know who you are.
No matter who you're talking to,
you shouldn't reveal your name or face to
anyone, unless it's absolutely necessary.
If I'm Kira, you're dead.
You're not Kira.
You're one of our allies.
Well, as for what I wanted
to talk to you about...
You think someone in the case
headquarters is connected to Kira?
It's true that the day after you profiled Kira,
the time of the killings changed.
In other words, the information was leaked.
Is that why you said you'd
only speak to one person?
Though I don't know why that person was me...
You're the type that always ends up on
the losing end of things, aren't you?
Unfortunately, the way things are right now,
the more trustworthy someone is,
the more they'll lose.
But it will be hard to pin down
where the leak is coming from.
Watari, show him.
This is...
I'm certain that Kira is one of these.
Ichigo Berry
You can invest your life in something,
and it might make you money,
but it won't necessarily make you happy.
Light! Can we talk?
Try not to talk to me outside, if possible.
Unlike you, people can hear me.
What I'm about to tell you
isn't because I'm on your side,
but just because it creeps me out.
What is it? Out with it already.
I'm always close to you, so I can tell...
there's a human who's been
following you around lately.
The FBI?
You're having American investigators check
out people related to the case squad?
Even their families?
Yes. This is one thing I can't
ask the Japanese police to do.
You think that guy's working with L?
As long as I can feed myself and
spend my days in peace and stability,
that's all I need.
Or so I thought.
Right, Light?
I understand. This is a battle.
I'm here!
Let's go.
Light... Top class!
Everyone got here early.
Hey, I heard before, the guy who
killed Misa Misa's family... he died.
A heart attack.
Oh, really?
Hello!
I have an announcement just for you guys!
Yeah? What is it?
This is just between us,
but something really good happened to me!
What happened?
I want this peace to
continue... that's why...
It's a secret!
Huh? Tell us!
But thanks to someone,
my heart was protected.
So today, I'm going to sing my heart out!
That's why I have to fight.
You've gone too far.
You shouldn't think of Kira as human.
He's the devil.
I need to find him and eliminate him:
L.
I'm going to find him no matter what:
Kira.
Even if I can't do it, Kira can.
Kira can
change the world.
They both need to find someone whose
face and name they don't know.
And whoever gets found first...
...will die.
Humans are just so damn interesting!
Hey, how do you think
those jerks will turn out, Near?
You shouldn't call them jerks.
It'll be worth watching. Kira and L...
who's going to fall apart first?
Near
Next Episode
The Shadow that Follows Light
We must catch Kira.
I'm going to go after Kira with L.
Your life is in danger!
The Impending End of Misa's Life
Kira...
It's gonna blow!
I'll eliminate anyone who gets in my way.
What did you do today?
You're Kira, aren't you?
Yagami Light...